Suraj Dey



surajdey8603@gmail.com

+918603709182



linkedin.com/in/suraj-dey-72822a124

Summary

Software Developer with 5+ years of experience in Java, Python-based Software/Web Application with strong analytical and problem-solving skills with demonstrated analysis solve complex problems with high efficiency and writing Quality Coding, Testing, Documentation in the areas of Development and Maintenance.

Skills

Data Structures • Algorithms • Spring Boot • Spring Data JPA • Spring ORM • Java • Apache Kafka • Elasticsearch • Hibernate • Jenkins • Distributed Systems • Microsoft Azure • Docker

Experience



Software Engineering MTS

Salesforce

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Sync Interactions with Einstein Activity Capture

Technology Used: Java, Elastic Search, Spring Framework, Kafka, PostgreSQL, EWS

- Built end to end product for Financial Institutions for Syncing of Event, Contact, Emails from Google and Microsoft.
- Scale the performance of the product with an Sync SLA from 50 Objects / 1 sec / Organization to 200 Objects / 1 sec / Organization
- Developed the core sync engine with custom validation of private event, selective event features.
- Implemented hash strategy to avoid round trip of events.

Activity Field History Tracking

Technology Used: Java, Hbase, Spring Framework, PostgreSQL

- Built tracking of change in any activity in salesforce objects like Event & Task.
- Built feature to support custom and encryption field for those Objects.
- Developed an algorithm to solve an existing issue for the Date field which gained 10-15 % customer trust.
- Fixed most of the bug bounty issues.

cft Programmer Analyst 2

Citi

Oct 2020 - Dec 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Smart Search Product

Technologies Used: Java, Elastic Search, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Hibernate, No SQL, SQL (Oracle), Cache(Encache).

- Developed search related API'S from starch for large scale systems (~1M Request/Day).
- Developed core functionality as per user preferences search using elastic search with low latency.
- Independently worked on requirement gathering and design and implementation of core functionality.
- Developed Tree Search filter using Breadth First Search Algorithm.
- Improved batch processing time (from 4 hour to 2 hour) from SQL DB to Elastic Index.
- Written JUnit for the services using Mockito with 100% coverage.

Common Inbox Dashboard

Technologies Used : Java, Kafka, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Hibernate, No SQL, SQL (Oracle), Cache (Redis)

- Developed Common Inbox Dashboard using asynchronisation message processing system using Kafka.
- Developed core functionality to convert entitlement of users.
- Implemented Custom Validation for Producer messages which prevent unwanted messages.
- Developed a batch process to archive message according to custom logic in real-time.



System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Oct 2017 - Sep 2020 (3 years)

Technologies Used: Java, XSLT, WSDL, Azure Cloud, Business Process Model

- Design and Developed an application for automatic failure notification through call service using Python and Flask web-service which made a profit of 5-10% increase in overall business.
- Developed Java libraries for commonly used components like HTTP Connector, JSON to XML Parser, CSV to XML Parser.
- Developed server less API using Azure Functions integrated with Azure API gateway.
- Migration from monolith architecture to micro service architecture deployed in the cloud using Azure Pipeline.
- Developed Supply Chain process using BPM Tool to integrate with different applications.

Education



Orissa Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical Engineering 2013 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



Building Deep Learning Models with TensorFlow - Coursera



Machine Learning with Python - Coursera

Projects

Healthy Food | JAVA, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Amazon S3, Oracle 19c

Design and Developed server-side Restful API'S for application using spring boot and security with JWT Token implementation.

• Flood Fill Algorithm | JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Developed Web Application to demonstrate the internal work of MS-Paint using Breadth First Search algorithm.

• Snapchat Feature | Python 3, Keras , OpenCV

Developed an AI algorithm which include face filter